Guide to the Keith McGee "Skylab Student Project" papers, 1962-1980 MS 044
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Keith McGee "Skylab Student Project" papers
1962-1980
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
McGee, Keith
MS 044
1.5 Linear Feet
The Keith McGee papers consist of correspondence, publications, and miscellaneous material collected while working on the "Skylab Student Project" at the Johnson Space Center in 1973. The collection includes photos, typed correspondence, printed material, and films.
Biographical Note
Keith McGee of Garland, TX was among 25 winners of a contest in which some 3,500 high school students proposed experiments for the following year's Skylab Mission. The nationwide scientific competition was sponsored by the National Science Teachers Association and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA). The winning students, along with their parents and sponsor teachers, visited MSFC where they met with scientists and engineers, participated in design reviews for their experiments, and toured MSFC facilities. Of the 25 students, 6 did not see their experiments conducted on Skylab because the experiments were not compatible with Skylab hardware and timelines. Of the 19 remaining, 11 experiments required the manufacture of additional equipment.
Scope and Contents
The Keith McGee papers consist of correspondence, publications, and other material collected while working on the "Skylab Student Project" at the Johnson Space Center in 1973. The collection includes photos, typed correspondence, printed material, and films.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift donated by Keith McGee on August 1, 1991.
Index Terms
Subjects
Space sciences; Universities and colleges
Document Types
letters (correspondence); clippings (information artifacts); reports; photographs
- Series I: Correspondence, 1970, 255387
  - Correspondence, 1970, 255388 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II: Publicity and published materials, 1962-1980, 255374
  - Newspaper articles (see also oversize, box 3), 255386 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Magazine articles, 255385 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Magazines: Time; Look; National Geographic, 255384 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Books: Man's Conquest of Space; Materials Processing in Space: Early Experiments, 255383 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Record: "First Man on the Moon", 255382 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - NASA Skylab Mission Chart, Nov. 10, 1973, 255381 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - NASA News, July 20, 1972, 255380 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Reel-to-reel tape: "Skylab" #ed. Z1 answer print, 255379 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Spacelab News Reference, 255378 (Box 2)
  - Gemini Press Reference Book, 255377 (Box 2)
  - Apollo Spacecraft News Reference Book, 255376 (Box 2)
  - Sticker (Box 2)
  - Oversize: Newpaper articles, 255375 (Box 3)